<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vertically Centering an Overlay Div</title>
      <link>/en/2021/01/vertically-centering-an-overlay-div/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2021/01/vertically-centering-an-overlay-div/</guid>
      <description>To vertically centering a div that overlays over another div, a simple solution is to set style of the top layer to top: 0; left:0; bottom:0; right:0;. However, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem work well if the background layer is scrollable. Here is another solution for vertically centering an overlay div is to use top: calc(50%-0.5*div.height), where the div.height is the height of the foreground div which can be calculated dynamically using javascript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting the Height of Div Dynamically Using JS</title>
      <link>/en/2021/01/setting-the-height-of-div-dynamically-using-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2021/01/setting-the-height-of-div-dynamically-using-js/</guid>
      <description>When using CSS-Doodle to create the background, one can use the CSS overlay trick (see for example How TO - Overlay). However, to create the CSS-Doodle background in the size of the text content. One can use CSS together with JS.
Here is an example.
&amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script&amp;gt; :root { --header-height: 0px; } &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script src=&amp;#34;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/jquery/3.5.0/jquery.min.js&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script&amp;gt; $(document).ready(function() { var height = $(&amp;#34;.header h1&amp;#34;).outerHeight(true) + &amp;#34;px&amp;#34;; document.documentElement.style.setProperty(&amp;#39;--header-height&amp;#39;, height)); }); &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;#34;container&amp;#34; style=&amp;#34;width: 100%; overflow: hidden; z-index: 2; position: relative;&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;css-doodle style=&amp;#34;position: relative; z-index: 1; height: calc(var(--header-height) + 1vh);&amp;#34;&amp;gt; :doodle { @grid: 20 / 100vmax; background: rgb(67, 134, 143, 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>用 CSS-Doodle 为网页添加几何美图</title>
      <link>/cn/2021/01/css-doodle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cn/2021/01/css-doodle/</guid>
      <description>最近试用了一下 CSS-Doodle, 效果很不错，见上图。 尽管官方教程已经非常清楚，但对于本人这种不太熟悉 CSS 的，学起来还是花了点时间。为了避免忘记，特以上图为例，</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing the Right Markdown Editor for Math</title>
      <link>/en/2021/01/choosing-the-right-markdown-editor-for-math/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2021/01/choosing-the-right-markdown-editor-for-math/</guid>
      <description>When using markdown for reproducible research , it is better to know how your writing will be rendered. That determines not only supported markdown syntax but also math typesetting.
Rendering Math It depends on the output (pdf or html), the following engines (all open sources) can be used to render math.
  LaTeX: used by Pandoc to render pdf.
  MathJax: rendering math in html.
 Easy to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>在 VS Code 中使用 R 的几个技巧</title>
      <link>/cn/2020/12/vscode-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cn/2020/12/vscode-r/</guid>
      <description>与 Rstudio 相比，VS Code 提供了更便捷有效的编辑环境。对于经常写 markdown 或者 Rmarkdown 温度的人来说，VS Code 应该是个更好的选择。而要将 markdown，尤其是 Rmarkdown 生成为</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>荷兰煎饼</title>
      <link>/cn/2020/12/dutch-baby-pancake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cn/2020/12/dutch-baby-pancake/</guid>
      <description>如果你有铸铁锅，且有30-40分钟时间，那么荷兰煎饼(Dutch Baby Pancake)绝对是简单又好吃的早餐选择之一。 食材及用量 面粉: 1 杯 鸡蛋:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knitr Code Chunk Labeling Issues</title>
      <link>/en/2020/12/knitr-code-chunk-labeling-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2020/12/knitr-code-chunk-labeling-issues/</guid>
      <description>When using Rmarkdown, we are recommended to assign to each code chunk an unique label that only contains alphanumeric characters (a-z, A-Z, 0-9), slashes (/), or dashes (-).
I never had taken the recommendation in serious consideration until I noticed that the string &amp;ldquo;unnamed_code_chunk&amp;rdquo; appeared in each theorem environment in the output pdf file. The reason that the string appears is because the underscore &amp;ldquo;_&amp;rdquo; is a special character in LaTeX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>在网页中使用思源宋体</title>
      <link>/cn/2020/12/siyuansongti/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cn/2020/12/siyuansongti/</guid>
      <description>前言 昨天从益辉的回复中我了解到了开源字体：思源宋体。于是就尝试了一把。由于 adobe 需要注册才能使用 Typekit 加载网络字体，而我一向不喜欢这种需要注册才能用</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Randomized Parameters in WebWork</title>
      <link>/en/2020/07/randomized-parameters-in-webwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2020/07/randomized-parameters-in-webwork/</guid>
      <description>WeBWorK uses of the language perl with extra packages to author questions.
A parameter/variable in Perl starts with &amp;ldquo;$&amp;rdquo;, for example $a, $integer, $var.
Supported by the PGrandom package, in WeBWork random variables can be defined.
One random number   Generates a random number between the initial and final values in steps of increment.
random( $initial, $final, $increment ) If the increment is 0 or less, then random chooses a floating point number between $initial and $final using a small increment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematics Recordings</title>
      <link>/en/2020/06/math-recordings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2020/06/math-recordings/</guid>
      <description>The post is simply for collecting recordings from famed mathematicians. The list will be kept updated.
  Prof. Jean Dieudonné: &amp;ldquo;The Historical Development of Algebraic Geometry&amp;rdquo;
  Serre: Finite groups, Yesterday and Today
  &amp;ldquo;How to write mathematics badly&amp;rdquo; by Jean-Pierre Serre
  John Conway: Surreal Numbers - How playing games led to more numbers than anybody ever thought of
  Differential Topology | Lectures by John W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Numbered Theorem Environments Using Pandoc</title>
      <link>/en/2020/04/pandoc-numbered-theorems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2020/04/pandoc-numbered-theorems/</guid>
      <description>When writing a research paper in a single html page, we can use Pandoc’s fenced Div blocks to create theorem environments. Using the css pseudo element ::before and counter property, we can add theorem name, number, and title to the theorem environment. Here is an example.
Suppose we have the theorem.
::: {.thm title=&amp;#34;(Fundamental Theorem of Algebra)&amp;#34; id=&amp;#34;thm:FTA&amp;#34;} Let $p(x)$ be a polynomial of degree $n&amp;gt;0$ with complex coefficients. Then $p(x)$ has exactly $n$ linear factors over the complex number field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools and Best Practice for Teaching Math Online</title>
      <link>/en/2020/03/best-practice-online-teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2020/03/best-practice-online-teaching/</guid>
      <description>Many teachers teach online using certain types of tools. I currently use a cloud meeting tool. A key feature for cloud meeting tools is to share contents. For math teacher, we frequently need to write math expression which is normally not so easy. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of painful using word. The learning curve of LaTeX is a little bit too steep. Luckily, for beginners, we have Markdown. Together with a handful editor, we can easily create documents for different purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redirect Netlify Sites</title>
      <link>/en/2020/03/redirect-netlify-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2020/03/redirect-netlify-sites/</guid>
      <description>Netlify is a great place to host a website directly from github. If you have multiple repositories and want to publish them under the same domain. There are two way to do it. You may also redirect a subdirectory of your personal site to a netlify site. However, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem possible to redirect a netlify site to a subdirectory.
Redirect netlify sites to domains or subdomains If you have a personal domain/subdomains, you can easily redirect a netlify site to your domain or a subdomain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling and Centering Figures for Rmarkdown</title>
      <link>/en/2020/03/scaling-centering-figs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2020/03/scaling-centering-figs/</guid>
      <description>There are different ways to include a picture in Rmarkdown. The basic way is to use ![caption](path/to/picture.extension). If the figure is not in an bookdown theorem environment, you may also use knitr.
```{r figure, echo=FALSE} knitr::include_graphics(path/to/picture.extension) ``` The way using knitr to include graphics provide more options to control the dimension and position of a figure. For details, you may read Yihui&amp;rsquo;s knitr manual on plots.
Because I normally have to include pictures in theorem environment in bookdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean LaTeX Commands For R Bookdown</title>
      <link>/en/2020/02/clean-latex-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2020/02/clean-latex-commands/</guid>
      <description>When using LaTeX template with customized theorem environments in R bookdown, you may see an error say a thereom environment is defined. Checking the output LaTex files, you will find that bookdown generated theorem enviroment at the end of the LaTeX preamble. To solve the problem, currently, one may use the magical bookdown.post.latex option. Adding the following code at the beginning of the index.Rmd file will remove the injected theorem environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Port Bookdown to Other Rmarkdown Format</title>
      <link>/en/2020/01/port-bookdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2020/01/port-bookdown/</guid>
      <description>In mathematics, we write a lot definitions, theorem etc. and refer to them in articles. However, among the Rmarkdown family, only bookdown has all those features that you need. Fortunately, Yihui created a feature base_format for bookdown which allows us to port it to amost all format in Rmarkdown family. Here is an example how you can do it and you may always want to write your yaml header in this way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>用Hugo创建中英混合博客</title>
      <link>/cn/2020/01/multilingual-blog-using-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cn/2020/01/multilingual-blog-using-hugo/</guid>
      <description>熟悉或者不熟悉 RStudio, 你都可以很快的用 blogdown 来创建一个私人博客。头一次创建，最容易当然是导入模板。以下我们将以 yihui/hugo-xmin 为例，简述一下怎样修改模板，从而创建如</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>松软蛋奶牛油包</title>
      <link>/cn/2020/01/soft-butter-milk-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cn/2020/01/soft-butter-milk-bread/</guid>
      <description>食材及用量 面粉: 3 杯 （略微多点少点没关系。） 大鸡蛋: 3 (如果用小一点的或者更大的鸡蛋可以调节牛奶的加入量。) 牛奶: 3/4 杯 (略微多点少点都可以。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The tikzDevice for R Users</title>
      <link>/en/2019/08/the-tikzdevice-for-r-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2019/08/the-tikzdevice-for-r-users/</guid>
      <description>What is the tikzDevice The tikzDevice is a R package that transforms R plots into $\LaTeX$ codes blocks. Those $\LaTeX$ codes can be complied by pdfLaTeX (or other $\TeX$ engines) with the help of TikZ — a graphics package for TeX and friends written by Till Tantau. On the website $\TeX$ample you may find many beautiful pictures created using TikZ/PGF (TikZ is a set of higher-level macros built on top of PGF).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install fonts in TeXLive</title>
      <link>/en/2019/05/how-to-install-fonts-in-texlive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2019/05/how-to-install-fonts-in-texlive/</guid>
      <description>After using LaTeX for a long time, you might be bored for default fonts and would like to install some new good looking fonts. If you will use XeTeX engine to compile your tex file, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about the installation. However, for pdfTeX engine, we do need a proper installation. If you use TeXLive like I do, you will complete the installation easily in three steps.
Where to install To make the fonts installation independent to distribution of TeXLive from different years, fonts should go into the local TEXMF-tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annotatable Webpages and Annotate Webpages</title>
      <link>/en/2019/04/annotatable-webpages-and-annotate-webpages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2019/04/annotatable-webpages-and-annotate-webpages/</guid>
      <description>Hypothesis, an online annotation tool Recently, I learned a cool online annotation tool, Hypothesis, which lets webpage readers add, share, explore and save annotations online for free.
What can Hypothesis do  Annotate and post publicly or save privately. Reply to or share any annotation publicly. Collaborate privately within a group. Explore public annotations and profiles.  For webpage creator Adding Hypothesis to a webpage is easy. You simply need to add the following codes in the head of you html file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Few Tips for Xaringan</title>
      <link>/en/2019/03/a-few-tips-for-xaringan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2019/03/a-few-tips-for-xaringan/</guid>
      <description>Add CSS Codes within RMarkdown When using Xaringan to create slides, one may include a custom.css or use the xaringanthemer package to change styles in whole or by part.
Recently, I found another trick that allow you make changes to styles within your rmarkdown file. It&amp;rsquo;s very simple. You simply only need to add a CSS code chunk1 at the beginning of your content.
Here is an example.
```{css, echo=F} .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some VBA Codes for Formating Tables</title>
      <link>/en/2019/02/some-vba-codes-for-formating-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2019/02/some-vba-codes-for-formating-tables/</guid>
      <description>Some VBA Codes for Formating Tables  Step 1: In Word -&amp;gt; File -&amp;gt; Options -&amp;gt; Customize Ribbon, check Developer in &amp;lsquo;Customize the ribbon&amp;rsquo; and click ok. Step 2: In Ribbons, find and click Developer -&amp;gt; Visual Basic (Alt+F11). Step 3: In the pop out windows, click Module on the Insert tab, copy and paste the following VBA code into the Module window and click the Run tab (F5) to run the macro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebWork Authoring Tips</title>
      <link>/en/2019/02/webwork-authoring-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2019/02/webwork-authoring-tips/</guid>
      <description>WebWork Text Display Languages   Original way using TEXT(EV3())
Example:
TEXT(EV3(&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;#39;END_TEXT&amp;#39;)); The material in this section is collected into a string which is then passed to the EV3 (evaluation 3 ) routine which handles processing of the sections in curly braces, then does interpolation, and finally processes the LaTeX commands. END_TEXT Remark:
  In the example two pg macros were used TEXT() and EV3(). Both macros are defined in PGbasicmacros.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create Multiple Pages in Blog Style with Jekyll</title>
      <link>/en/2019/02/how-to-create-multiple-pages-in-blog-style-with-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2019/02/how-to-create-multiple-pages-in-blog-style-with-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Multiple Blogs on One Site1 Suppose that you have two categories of blogs. There are two ways to create directories in your website folder
  --blog1 |--_posts --blog2 |--_post   |--_posts |--blog1 |--blog2   The first approach will automatically assign categories to your posts.
Using the second approach, you will need to manually add category: your_blog_folder_name to Yaml Front Matter in each post.
--- layout: default title: Blog1 category: blog1 --- You also need to modify the default layout template for the category blog1 by adding a filter using post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Links Open in New Windows/Tab for Markdown</title>
      <link>/en/2019/02/make-links-open-in-new-windows/tab-for-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2019/02/make-links-open-in-new-windows/tab-for-markdown/</guid>
      <description>Using jQuery to Open External Links in New Windows1 Creating (static) webpages using markdown is every convenient, for example
[Queensborough Community College](http://www.qcc.cuny.edu). However, left clicking a link by default opens it in the same window. If there are only a few links, one may use html codes to open a link in a new window, for example
&amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;http://www.qcc.cuny.edu&amp;#34; target=&amp;#34;_blank&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Queensborough Community College&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. When there are many links it will be a little bit painful to create such links using html in a markdown file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for RStudio Setup for RMarkdown and More</title>
      <link>/en/2019/02/tips-for-rstudio-setup-for-rmarkdown-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2019/02/tips-for-rstudio-setup-for-rmarkdown-and-more/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t install R to the default location. Instead, choose a location such as C:\Program Files\R.
Verdict: no version difference issue
  Create a .Renviron file to your home directory ~/ using the following function:
# File will be created if it doesn&amp;#39;t exist file.edit(&amp;#39;~/.Renviron&amp;#39;) Add R_LIBS_USER=&amp;quot;C:/R&amp;quot; to .Renviron. This variable will be the library of R packages. It is extremely useful if you are using a computer with limited rights and anti-virus softwares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Online LaTeX and Markdown Editors</title>
      <link>/en/2018/10/useful-online-latex-and-markdown-editors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2018/10/useful-online-latex-and-markdown-editors/</guid>
      <description>LaTeX   ShareLaTeX which is integrated with Overleaf now.
Online LaTeX editors and best for working individully or collaboratively online.
  TeXLive + Visual Studio Code + LaTeX Workshop.
Very productive combination for writing LaTeX.
  Markdown   StackEdit
Online Markdown editor and good for writing simple documents and converting them into different format.
  Typora
Very impressive offline Markdown WYSIWYG editor. Very powerful in converting markdown to other formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Videos on Mathematics</title>
      <link>/en/2018/08/online-videos-on-mathematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2018/08/online-videos-on-mathematics/</guid>
      <description>List of some links to online videos on Mathematics (mostly Algebraic Geometry).   ICM Videos
  MSRI VMath
  Isaac Newton Institute for Mathematical Sciences
  Vod the MathNet Korea
  MathNet Russia
  Clay Mathematics Institute
  Institute of Advanced Study
  Duke Mathematics Department
  Atiyah80 Video Lectures
  Southwest Center Streaming Video
  Foundation Sciences Mathématiques de Paris</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
